### SILAS ASIEDU ASAMOAH



silasasieduasamoah@gmail.com

(+233) 202-933-060



(in) LinkedIn Profile

### **Personal Details**

Gender: Male Nationality: Ghanaian

Date of Birth: 8th Feb. 1996

# Summary

Electrical Engineer with experience in utilizing modern tools in design and evaluation of renewable energy systems as well as competence in Computer Aided Design (CAD) tools in mitigating engineering problems. Highly motivated team player with excellent interpersonal and communication skill.

# **Work Experience**

STELLA FUTURA LTD

Sept 2019 - Present

Accra-Greater Accra

### Design Engineer.

- Responsible for PV System energy demand analysis, system sizing and design.
- Responsible for PV System Monitoring and Reporting.

**UENR SOLAR INSTALLTION GROUP** 

June 2018 - Sept 2018

Sunyani-Bono Region

### Intern.

- Assisted in solar street light installation.
- Engaged in residential solar system sizing, design, and efficient energy management.

NORTHERN ELECTRICITY DISTRIBUTION COMPANY

June 2017 - Sept 2017

Sunyani-Bono Region

#### Intern.

• Assisted in post-paid and prepaid energy meter inspection, maintenance and replacement.

### **Education**

### BSC Electrical and Electronic Engineering.

Sept 2015 - July 2019

University of Energy and Natural Resources (UENR)

Sunyani-Bono Region

### **Technical**

In-dept knowledge and expertise in:

- Energy System Simulation Software: PVSol, PVSyst, AutoCAD Electrical, Sunny Web Design, SketchUp.
- Data Analysis and Visualization with Python
- MS Office: VBA, Excel, Word and PowerPoint.

### Other

- Comprehensive knowledge and skill in Solar Systems
- Knowledgeable in Front-end Web Development.

# Languages

English Language, fluent

Asante Twi, native language.

#### **Interests**

Fixing Electrical Gadgets, Listening to Music, Playing Chess, Reading.

#### References

• Ing. Emmanuel Yeboah Asuamah

University of Energy and Natural Resources (UENR)

Assistant Research Fellow

0540463768

• Mr Isaac Otchere

University of Energy and Natural Resources (UENR)

Senior Lecturer

0558221405

• Mr Samuel Sarquar

Northern Energy Distribution Company (NEDCO)

0209065896